A Finding Aid to the Forbes Watson Papers, 1840-1967, bulk 1900-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.watsforb
Archives of American Art
Forbes Watson papers
bulk 1900-1960
1840-1967
AAA.watsforb
Archives of American Art
13.5 Linear feet
The papers of New York City art critic, writer, and lecturer Forbes Watson date from 1840-1967 with the bulk of materials dating from 1900-1960 and measure 13.5 linear feet. Found are biographical materials, correspondence, business records relating to the Arts Publishing Corporation, records documenting Watson's work for the Public Works of Art Project and the Section of Painting and Sculpture, reference files, an exhibition file from the Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition, writings and notes, ten scrapbooks and loose pages, printed materials, and photographs.
Watson, Forbes
Provenance
The Forbes Watson papers were donated by Watson's widow, Nan Watson, in 1961.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Forbes Watson (1879-1960) worked primarily in New York City and Washington, D.C. as an art critic, writer, lecturer, and consultant to the U. S. Treasury Department's Public Works of Art Project and Section of Painting and Sculpture (Section of Fine Arts).
Forbes Watson was born on November 27, 1879 in Boston, the son of stockbroker John Watson and his wife Mary. Watson grew up in Cambridge, Massachusetts, attending the Phillips Academy in Andover, and graduating from Harvard University in 1902. After a brief period of freelance writing, he was hired by The New York Evening Post as an art critic in 1911 and worked there until 1917. In 1910, he married Agnes, professionally known as painter Nan Watson.
During World War I, Watson served with an American volunteer ambulance unit with the French army, later working with the American Red Cross in Paris. After the war, he moved back to New York City and worked as art critic for The World, from the early 1920s until 1931 and as editor of The Arts magazine from 1923-1933. Watson also lectured at the Art Students League, and at various universities and arts organizations.
In 1933, Watson moved to Washington, D.C. to serve as technical director of the U. S. Treasury Department's short-lived Public Works of Art Project. In October 1934, Watson was employed as Chief Adviser to the Treasury Department's Section of Painting and Sculpture (later renamed the Section of Fine Arts) and later as Consultant to the Secretary's Office of the Treasury. During World War II, he organized various traveling exhibitions including "Art for Bonds" that promoted the sale of war bonds. Watson retired in 1946 and lived in Gaylordsville, Connecticut.
Watson was the author of numerous essays and reviews, and several books including American Painting Today and Winslow Homer, a biography of the noted American artist. With Edward Bruce, he produced a pictorial volume Art in Federal Buildings, Vol. I: Mural Designs. At his death he was working on his autobiography.
Forbes Watson died on May 31, 1960 in New Milford, Connecticut.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of New York City art critic, writer, and lecturer Forbes Watson date from 1840-1967 with the bulk of materials dating from 1900-1960 and measure 13.5 linear feet. Found are biographical materials, correspondence, business records relating to the Arts Publishing Corporation, records documenting Watson's work for the Public Works of Art Project and the Section of Painting and Sculpture, reference files, an exhibition file from the Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition, writings and notes, ten scrapbooks and loose pages, printed materials, and photographs.
Biographical material includes Watson's Harvard diploma, documents concerning his service with the Red Cross in World War II, biographical accounts, and obituaries.
Correspondence is primarily with colleagues and includes scattered letters from Alfred H. Barr, Jr., Ira Glackens, Allen Tucker, and Max Weber. Other letters are from artists, art historians, and museum curators. A notebook contains shorthand drafts of letters from Watson.
Business records include personal business records consisting of various tax and stock records. The Arts Publishing Corporation records concern Watson's tenure as editor of The Arts magazine and contains a contract, correspondence, financial records, stockholders reports, press releases, a scrapbook, and issues of The Arts.
The U.S. Treasury Department file is the largest series and documents Watson's federal employment as technical director, chief advisor, and consultant for Treasury Department's public art programs - the Public Works of Art Project and the Section of Painting and Sculpture. The files contain correspondence, financial reports, prospectuses, exhibition files, typescripts, clippings, exhibition catalogs, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs, and a scrapbook. The files contain a record of Watson's and other federal administrators' interactions with many artists during the Depression Era. Correspondence is primarily between Watson and Edward Bruce, Olin Dows, Henry and Elinor Morgenthau, and Edward B. Rowan. Found are scattered letters from artists including Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Paul Manship, and William Zorach, among many others. There are exhibition files for "Art for Bonds," "Army at War," and "War Against Japan." There are also photographs of U. S. Treasury Department events including a radio broadcast by John Dewey, Robert La Follette, Jr., and Sumner Welles.
Documents from the Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition at the National Academy of Design contains a prospectus, an exhibition catalog and artists' statements.
Artist/Patron files contain reference material concerning painters, sculptors, photographers, dancers, composers, authors, art collectors, art dealers, and museum administrators. Files may include writings, notes, artworks, exhibition catalogs and other printed materials. Of particular note are photographs, which include portrait photographs of artists and of artists in their studios. Notable photographers include Ansel Adams, Arnold Genthe, Man Ray, photographs of New York City by Charles Sheeler and a photo of Henri Matisse by A. E. Gallatin. Files for Nan Watson, Symeon Shimin, and Glenn O. Coleman contain artworks. A file for Constantin Brancusi contains legal documents concerning U. S. Customs vs. Brancusi.
Art and Architecture files consist of reference material including photographs and notes concerning miscellaneous unattributed art works, American architecture, and furnishings.
Notes and writings consist of miscellaneous notes and typescripts of lectures and published articles, and notebooks.
Nine scrapbooks and loose scrapbook pages contain clippings of articles written by Watson, lists, and exhibition announcements and catalogs. Additional printed material includes clippings, copies of the Hue and Cry newspaper, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, calendars of events, brochures for the Art Students League, book catalogs, published books, and miscellaneous printed material.
Photographs are of Forbes Watson; family members including his wife, painter Nan Watson; and members of the Art Students League including Peggy Bacon, Minna Citron, Stewart Klonis, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, and Reginald Marsh. There are also photographs of juries for the Carnegie Institute International Exhibitions that include colleagues Alfred H. Barr, Jr., Gifford Beal, Guy Pene DuBois, Leon Kroll, Henri Matisse, Homer Saint-Gaudens, and Maurice Sterne.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1902-1960 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1913-1960 (Box 1; 33 folders)
Series 3: Business Records, 1920-1942 (Box 1-3, 14; 2.0 linear feet)
Series 4: U. S. Treasury Department File, 1926-1945 (Box 3-6, 14, 17, OV 21; 3.4 linear feet)
Series 5: File for Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition "Paintings of the Year," 1946 (Box 6; 5 folders)
Series 6: Artist/Patron Files, 1840-1967 (Box 6-9, 15, OV 21; 2.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Art and Architecture File, 1929-1930 (Box 9; 35 folders)
Series 8: Notes and Writings, 1875-1950 (Box 9-10; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 9: Scrapbooks, 1904-1951 (Box 9, 11, 14, BV 18, BV 19, BV 20; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 10: Printed Material, 1900-1961 (Box 10, 12-13, 16-17; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 11: Photographs, 1900-1950 (Box 13; 6 folders)
All material is arranged chronologically, with the exception of the Artist/Patron Files which are arranged alphabetically.
Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Art Students League (New York, N.Y.).; Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1902-1981; Beal, Gifford, 1879-1956 -- Photographs; Brancusi, Constantin, 1876-1957; Bruce, Edward, 1879-1943; Citron, Minna Wright, 1896-1991; Coleman, Glenn O., 1887-1932; Dows, Olin, 1904-1981; Du Bois, Guy Pène, 1884-1958; Gallatin, A. E. (Albert Eugene), 1881-1952; Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942; Glackens, Ira, 1907-1990; Klonis, Stewart, 1901-1989; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974 -- Photographs; Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953; Kuniyoshi, Yasuo, 1889-1953 -- Photographs; Mangravite, Peppino, 1896-; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954 -- Photographs; Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954; Morgenthau, Henry, 1891-1967; Pepsi-Cola Company; Public Works of Art Project; Ray, Man, 1890-1976; Red Cross.; Rowan, Edward Beatty, 1898-1946; Saint-Gaudens, Homer, b. 1880 -- Photographs; Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965; Shimin, Symeon, 1902-; Sterne, Maurice, 1878-1957; Tucker, Allen, 1866-1939; United States. Dept. of the Treasury. Section of Fine Arts.; United States. Dept. of the Treasury. Section of Painting and Sculpture.; United States. Public Buildings Administration. Section of Fine Arts.; Watson, Nan, 1876-1966; Weber, Max, 1881-1961; Zorach, William, 1887-1966; Architecture, New York State, New York--Photographs; Architecture--New York, N.Y.--Photographs; Art and state; Art critics--New York (State)--New York; Art publishing; Art, American; Arts (Magazine); Arts administrators--New York (State)--New York; Authors--New York (State)--New York; Drafts (documents); Federal aid to the arts; New Deal, 1933-1939; New York N.Y.--Buildings, structures, etc., Photographs; Notes; Photographs; Scrapbooks; United States--Social conditions--1933-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war
- Biographical Material, 1902-1960; Series 1; (Box 1; 4 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consists of Watson's Harvard diploma, documents concerning his service with the Red Cross in World War II, biographical accounts, and obituaries.
  - Harvard Diploma, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Documents Concerning World War I Service in the Red Cross, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Accounts, 1932-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries for Forbes Watson, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1913-1960; Series 2; (Box 1; 34 folders)
  The correspondence series contains letters regarding general topics. A notebook contains shorthand drafts of letters from Watson to Concetta Scaravaglione, Eugene Speicher, Margit Varga, and Jane Wasey, among others. Correspondence is primarily with colleagues and includes scattered letters from Alfred H. Barr, Jr., Ira Glackens, Allen Tucker, and Max Weber. There are also scattered letters from Gifford Beal, George Bellows, Thomas Hart Benton, George Biddle, Isabel Bishop, Stirling Calder, Mabel Choate, Andrew Dasburg, Guy Pene Du Bois, Juliana Force, Albert E. Gallatin, Robert Henri, Edward Hopper, William James, Robert Laurent, Reginald Marsh, Duncan Phillips, Henry Varnum Poor, Henry E. Schnakenberg, Aaron Sopher, Raphael Soyer, Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, and Virginia Woolf.
  - Shorthand Notebook of Letters from Watson, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "A" - "C,", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "D,", undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "H" - "R,", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondents with Surnames "S" - "Z,", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1913-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1925; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Correspondence, 1926; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence, 1927; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1929; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Correspondence, 1930; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Correspondence, 1931; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1954; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Business Records, 1920-1942; Series 3; (Box 1-3, 14; 2.0 linear feet)
  Found are records relating to Watson's personal business and the Arts Publishing Corporation.
  Arrangement note
  The Business Records series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  Subseries 3.1: Personal Business Records, 1937-1942
  Subseries 3.2: Arts Publishing Corporation Records, 1920-1932
  - Personal Business Records, 1937-1942; 3.1
    Found are tax and stock records.
    - Personal Business, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Arts Publishing Corporation Records, 1920-1932; 3.2
    Found are materials concerning Watson's tenure as editor of The Arts magazine, including legal records, corresopndence, financial materials, stockholder reports, printed material, and a scrapbook. Also found are issues of The Arts dating from 1921 until 1931.
    - Contract, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1932; (7 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-47)
    - Advertising Costs, 1923-1930 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Subscriptions, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Stockholders Report, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Brochures, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Press Releases, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - The Arts, 1920-1924; (16 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-68)
    - The Arts, 1924-1928; (18 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-18)
    - The Arts, 1929-1931; (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
    - Scrapbook, 1923-1931 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- U.S. Treasury Department records, 1926-1945; Series 4; (Boxes 3-6, 14, 17, OV 21; 3.4 linear feet)
  This series contains correspondence, financial materials, mural competition files, exhibition files, writings and lists, printed mateirals including exhibition catalogs, and photographs related to Watson's work for the U.S. Treasury Department.
  The U.S. Treasury Department records series is arranged into 8 subseries:
  Subseries 4.1: Correspondence, 1933-1945
  Subseries 4.2: Business and Financial Records, 1935-1942
  Subseries 4.3: Mural Competition Files, 1935-1939
  Subseries 4.4: Exhibition Files, 1942-1945
  Subseries 4.5: Writings and Lists, 1934-1945
  Subseries 4.6: Printed Material, 1934-1945
  Subseries 4.7: Photographs, 1934, undated
  Subseries 4.8: Scrapbooks, 1944-1945
  - Correspondence, 1933-1945; 4.1
    This subseries consists of correspondence between Watson and Edward Bruce, Olin Dows, Henry and Elinor Morgenthau and Edward B. Rowan.
    - Chronological, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Chronological, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Chronological, 1936; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
    - Chronological, 1937; (3 folders; Oversized material housed in OV21) (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
    - Chronological, 1938; (13 folders) (Box 3, Folder 19-31)
    - Chronological, 1939; (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 32-41)
    - Chronological, 1940; (7 folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-48)
    - Chronological, 1942; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 49-52)
    - Chronological, 1942; (7 folders) (Box 3, Folder 53-59)
    - Chronological, 1943; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Chronological, 1944; (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 3-10)
    - Chronological, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Oversized Christmas Card by Peppino Mangravite, 1937; (from Box 3, F18) (Box OV 21)
  - Business and Financial Records, 1935-1942; 4.2
    - Inspection Tour File, 1937; (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 12-15)
    - Financial Summary Reports, 1935-1942 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - National competitions Committee Report, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Mural Competition Files, 1935-1939; 4.3
    This subseries contains four prospectuses for various mural competitions at post offices throughout the United States sponsored by the U.S. Treasury Department. Another prospectus is for the Forty-Eight State competition.
    - Dubuque, Iowa, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Summerville, Massachusetts, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Poughkeepsie, New York, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Wausau, Wisconsin, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Forty-Eight State Competition, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition Files, 1942-1945; 4.4
    This subseries consists of correspondence, writings, notes, printed materials, and photographs
    The Exhibition Files series is arranged into 3 subseries:
    Subseries 4.4.1: "Art for Bonds," 1942-1945
    Subseries 4.4.2: "Army at War," 1943-1945
    Subseries 4.4.3: "War Against Japan," 1944-1945
    - "Art for Bonds,", 1942-1945; 4.4.1
      The "Art for Bonds" exhibition promoted the sale of war bonds during World War II. Found are letters of correspondence, litsts of works of art and of patrons, notes, press releases, writings, and printed materials. Typescripts of Watson's letters to his wife describe his activities in Paris while he organized the "Art for Bonds."
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, 1943; (15 folders) (Box 4, Folder 24-38)
      - Correspondence, 1944; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
      - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 41-43)
      - From Forbes Watson to Nan Watson, 1945; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 44-46)
        (Describes Watson's activities while organizing "Art for Bonds" in Paris, France)
      - Lists of Works of Art, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Lists of Art Patrons, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Captions, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Press Releases, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Lectures, 1943; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
      - "Concerning Life at Camp Barnes in New Caledonia," by Unknown, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Forward for a Catalog by Elinor B. Morgentuau, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Clippings, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Programs, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Posters, undated; (Oversized material housed in OV21) (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Brochure, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Photographs of the Exhibition in Paris, France, 1945; (14 folders) (Box 4, Folder 61-74)
      - Oversized Poster, undated; (from Box 4, F59) (Box OV 21)
    - "Army at War,", 1943-1945; 4.4.2
      Found are correspondence, a typescript for a radio talk, writings and lectures, reports, printed materials, and photographs. Photographs include those of Henry Morgenthau, Forbes Watson and Eleanor Roosevelt at exhibitions as well as exhibition photographs from New York City, Buffalo, Detroit, Chicago, Minneapolis, Portland, Los Angeles, and Denver.
      - Correspondence, 1944; (Oversized material housed in OV21; 20 folders) (Box 4, Folder 75-94)
      - Correspondence, 1945; (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 95-102)
      - Radio Talk Typescript, 1944-1945; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 103-105)
      - "Our Artists Paint the Army at War,", 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Lecture, Rochester, New York, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Exhibition Report, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Writings and Notes, 1944, undated; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 4-10)
      - Clippings, 1944-1945; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 11-17)
      - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1944; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 18-19)
      - Press Releases, 1944; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
      - Photographs of Exhibitions (Box 5)
        - Washington, D.C., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 22)
          (Henry Morgenthau and Forbes Watson, held at National Gallery of Art)
        - 1944, New York City, New York; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
          (Eleanor Roosevelt)
        - Buffalo, New York, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        - Detroit, Michigan, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        - Chicago, Illinois, 1944; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
        - Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 29)
        - Portland, Oregon, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 30)
        - Los Angeles, California, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 31)
        - Denver, Colorado, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Negatives of Works of Art, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Oversized Floor Plan for Detroit Exhibition, 1944; (from Box 4, F89) (Box OV 21)
    - "War Against Japan,", 1944-1945; 4.4.3
      Found are correspondence, artist biographies, lists and writings, printed material, and photographs of service men, David Finley, Henry Morgenthau, Forbes Watson, and art work.
      - Correspondence, 1945; (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 34-39)
      - Artist Biographies, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Lists of Works of Art, 1944-1945; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 41-42)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - "War Against Japan,", undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Printed Materials, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Photographs (Box 5)
        - Service Men and Artwork, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
        - Washington, D.C., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 47)
          (David Finley, Henry Morgenthau, and Forbes Watson at the National Gallery of Art)
        - Works of Art, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Wrtitings and Lists, 1934-1945; 4.5
    Found are lists concerning artwork, art patrons, artists, and purchases; transcripts of radio talks by Forbes Watson, Edward Bruce, Mrs. Henry Morgenthau and Mrs. Esther Van Wagoner Tufty; typescripts of writings, lectures, and talks, the majority of which do not have specified authors and are undated; and miscellaneous notes.
    - Lists (Box 5)
      - Mural Painters and Locations, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Lecture Slides, undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 50-52)
      - Works of Art, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Sponsors, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Artists, undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
      - Artists' Addresses, 1938, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
      - Artists and Works, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - Works of Art, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 58)
        (Works purchased by the Office of Emergency Management)
      - Publications Concerning Art, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Notes Concerning Artists War Program in New England, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Radio Talk, Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Typescripts of Radio Talks and Interviews (Box 5)
      - Forbes Watson and Edward Bruce, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 62)
      - Forbes Watson by Mrs. Richard Casey of Australia, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      - Forbes Watson by Charles Coiner, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 64)
        (From Home of the Brave Radio Program)
      - Mrs Henry Morgenthau and Mrs. Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Lecture Manuscript, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - "An American Experiment in Art,", undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - "American Mural Painting,", undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - "The Army Artist Unit" and "Art in the U.S.A.,", undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - "Art in Federal Buildings,", undated (Box 5, Folder 70-71)
    - "Art in the Democracy" and "Art in the Storms,", undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - "Art in War Time" and "Art is a Weapon,", undated (Box 5, Folder 73)